rsna.org 2019-12-11

# RSNA Privacy Policy

We only collect and use personal data when there is a fair and legal basis for its collection and use, for instance, when the collection of personal data is necessary to become member of the Society, to meet our legitimate interests to send marketing material, to comply with legal obligations or when we have your authorization. See below the legal basis for each collection:

  * Membership information: necessity to enter into a contract or for the performance of a contract and legitimate interest
  * Registration to events, conferences and the annual meeting: necessity to enter into or for the performance of a contract. For certain processing of personal data in relation to our events, we rely on legitimate interest (e.g. taking photos during the event) to advance our mission as a membership organization in providing education and information.
  * Marketing activities: Consent for email marketing; our legitimate interests for marketing conducted other than through email or phone call;
  * Business information: necessity to enter into a contract or for the performance of a contract
  * Videos and photos: Legitimate interest for informational and educational activities with consent to use specific images and video
  * Mobile App: legitimate interest to assist Annual Meeting attendees navigate and organize their meeting experience and consent
  * Journal submissions: necessity to enter or for the performance of a contract
  * Information collected automatically: consent

Privacy rights under the European regulation:  
**Transparency and the right to information:** we provide notice to our members, website users and other third parties who interact with us of how we use personal data in our day-to-day activities at the time of collecting personal data, or as soon thereafter as possible. We also publish this privacy notice for a greater transparency.  
**Right to access, rectification, restriction of processing, erasure, and data portability:** if you are based in the EEA we provide you with access to your own personal data. In addition, we will rectify your personal data when it is incorrect or inaccurate, and we will ensure the right to erasure, portability and to restriction of processing when these rights are not incompatible with other legal obligations.   
**Right to object and withdraw consent at any time:** for all marketing materials, you can opt-out anytime, and free of charge. The right to object for other processing activities will be balanced to ensure that it is not incompatible with local regulations or our legitimate interests.   
These requests should be submitted as follows: 

  * Opt-out of marketing communications: you can opt-out anytime by following the opt-out instructions in our commercial e-mails or [contacting](mailto:privacy@rsna.org) us. You will still continue to receive emails relevant to course registrations or purchases (e.g. registration confirmations or purchase receipts) or necessary to your continued membership in RSNA (e.g. dues notices).
  * To exercise the rest of your rights: you should send a communication in writing to:

Radiological Society of North America  
Attn: Privacy  
820 Jorie Boulevard   
Suite 200  
Oak Brook, Illinois 60523, USA

In order to fulfil this request,we may require you provide us information to verify your identity and specify your request. We will attend to your request in a timely manner within 30 days after receiving your request. If for any reason we need to extend this period of time, we will contact you.

If you are not satisfied with our response,you have the **right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority** of your habitual residence, place of work or place of the alleged infringement.
